Innocence is what he knows. Beauty is what she sees.
Edward Scissorhands is a fantasy, drama, romance film directed by Tim Burton.
A small suburban town receives a visit from a castaway
unfinished science experiment named Edward.
Edward Scissorhands, played by Johnny Depp.
Kim, played by Winona Ryder.
Peg, played by Dianne Wiest.
Jim, played by Anthony Michael Hall.
Joyce, played by Kathy Baker.
Kevin, played by Robert Oliveri.
Edward Scissorhands is a 1990 American Gothic romantic
fantasy film directed by Tim Burton.
It was produced by Burton and Denise Di Novi, written by Caroline Thompson from a story by her and Burton, and starring Johnny Depp as the
title character, along with Winona Ryder,  Dianne Wiest, Anthony Michael Hall, Kathy Baker, Vincent Price, and Alan Arkin.
It tells the story of an unfinished artificial humanoid who has scissor blades instead of hands,
is taken in by a suburban family, and falls in love with their teenage daughter.
Burton conceived Edward Scissorhands from his childhood
upbringing in suburban Burbank, California.
During pre-production of Beetlejuice, Thompson was hired to adapt Burton's story into a
screenplay, and the film began development at 20th Century Fox after Warner Bros.
Edward Scissorhands was then fast-tracked after Burton's
critical and financial success with Batman.
The film also marks the fourth collaboration between Burton and film score composer Danny
Elfman, and was Vincent Price's last film role to be released in his lifetime.
Edward Scissorhands was a critical and commercial success,
grossing over four times its $20 million budget.
The film won the British Academy Film Award for Best Production Design and the Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation, in
addition to receiving multiple nominations at the Academy Awards, British Academy Film Awards, and the Saturn Awards.
Both Burton and Elfman consider Edward Scissorhands
their most personal and favorite work.
The film explores themes of underdog, small town,
unsociability, inventor, hairdresser.
The tone is emotional.